A Guide to the English Village Corporation (Richmond, Va.) Records, 1927-1952
Library of Virginia
Library of Virginia
English Village Corporation (Richmond, Va.) Records, 1927-1952
The Library of Virginia
51129
.45 cubic feet (1 box)
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
Purchased.
Historical Information
English Village is an early twentieth-century Tudor styled multi-family residence located in the 3400 block of Grove Avenue in Richmond, Virginia. It was designed by Bascom J. Rowlett, a Richmond architect, and was one of the first cooperatives in the city and an example of a 1920's planned community. English Village was incorporated on 14 April 1927. In 1947, the original landscaping plan was altered by Charles Gilette, a Richmond landscape architect. It is currently listed on the National Register of Historic Places, both individually, as well as within the context of the Richmond's West of Boulevard Historic District (Museum District).
Scope and Content
Records, 1927-1952, of the English Village Corporation of Richmond, Virginia, containing correspondence regarding board of directors' and stockholders' meetings, complaints, elections of officers, lease renewals and sales of units, legal proceedings, maintenance and landscaping, operating expenses, parking, resolutions, taxes and assessments, tenants and property owners' rules and regulations, and other matters. The files were kept by Robert Leroy Atwell (1892-1971), who was a property owner, stockholder, and corporation president.
Contents List
- 1931. (Box 1, Folder 1)
- 1933. (Box 1, Folder 2)
- 1934. (Box 1, Folder 3)
- 1935. (Box 1, Folder 4)
- 1936. (Box 1, Folder 5)
- 1937. (Box 1, Folder 6)
- 1938. (Box 1, Folder 7)
- 1942. (Box 1, Folder 8)
- 1944. (Box 1, Folder 9)
- 1945. (Box 1, Folder 10)
- 1946. (Box 1, Folder 11)
- 1949. (Box 1, Folder 12)
- 1950. (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Batkins, Mary W. (Mrs. Ernest A.). (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Board of Directors, 1949. (Box 1, Folder 15)
- Butler, W.E.. (Box 1, Folder 16)
- Heating Boiler. (Box 1, Folder 17)
- Janitor. (Box 1, Folder 18)
- Lease Forms. (Box 1, Folder 19)
- Miscellaneous. (Box 1, Folder 20)
- Operations Bills - Lawsuit, 1946. (Box 1, Folder 21)
- Playground. (Box 1, Folder 22)
- President's Expenditures. (Box 1, Folder 23)
- Resolutions. (Box 1, Folder 24)
- Sale Contract, 1927. (Box 1, Folder 25)
- Spain, William Eldridge. (Box 1, Folder 26)
- Special Stockholders' Meetings, 1944. (Box 1, Folder 27)
- Special Stockholders' Meetings, 1946. (Box 1, Folder 28)
- Special Stockholders' Meetings, 1949. (Box 1, Folder 29)
- Stationary. (Box 1, Folder 30)
- Stockholders' Letter, 9 September 1946. (Box 1, Folder 31)
- Stockholders' Letter, 17 September 1946. (Box 1, Folder 32)
- Stockholders' Letter, 20 September 1946. (Box 1, Folder 33)
- Stockholders' Letter, 26 October 1947. (Box 1, Folder 34)
- Tax Assessment Study, 1952. (Box 1, Folder 35)
- Unpaid Bills. (Box 1, Folder 36)